A man who believed in war! A man who believed in nothing!
And a woman who believed in both of them!
Coming Home is a drama, romance, war film directed by Hal Ashby.
In 1968 California, a Marine officer's wife falls in love with a former high
school classmate who suffered a paralyzing combat injury in the war.
Sally Hyde, played by Jane Fonda.
Luke Martin, played by Jon Voight.
Capt. Bob Hyde, played by Bruce Dern.
Vi Munson, played by Penelope Milford.
Bill Munson, played by Robert Carradine.
Sgt. Dink Mobley, played by Robert Ginty.
Coming Home is a 1978 American romantic war drama film directed by Hal
Ashby from a screenplay written by Waldo Salt and Robert C.
Jones with story by Nancy Dowd.
It stars Jane Fonda, Jon Voight, Bruce Dern, Penelope
Milford, Robert Carradine and Robert Ginty.
The film's narrative follows a perplexed woman, her Marine husband, and a paraplegic Vietnam War veteran
with whom she develops a romantic relationship while her husband is deployed in Vietnam.
Coming Home was theatrically released on February 15,
1978, to critical and commercial success.
Reviewers praised its direction, screenplay, and performances, while the film grossed $36 million
worldwide against its $3 million budget, becoming the 15th highest-grossing film of 1978.
It also premiered at the 1978 Cannes Film Festival, where it competed for
the Palme d'Or, with Voight winning the Best Actor Prize.
The film received various awards and nominations.
At the 36th Golden Globe Awards, it received six nominations including for the Best Motion
Picture – Drama, with Voight and Fonda winning Best Actor and Best Actress.
At the 51st Academy Awards, it received eight nominations including for the Best Picture, winning
three; Best Original Screenplay, with Voight and Fonda winning Best Actor and Best Actress.
The film explores themes of vietnam war, california, vietnam,
post-traumatic stress disorder (ptsd), paraplegic.
The tone is emotional.